groove.co 2019-12-02

# Groove

**Last Updated: June 6th, 2017**

We at Groove know you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. **By using or accessing the Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.**

Remember that unless you and Groove have otherwise entered into a written agreement specifically governing your use of Groove’s Services (and specifically excluding the Terms of Service), your use of Groove’s Services is at all times subject to the [Terms of Service](http://grooveapp.com/terms), which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the [Terms of Service](http://grooveapp.com/terms). 

### What does this Privacy Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that we gather when you are accessing or using our Services, but not to the practices of companies we don’t own or control, or people that we don’t manage. We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained in more detail below, and we use this Personal Information internally in connection with our Services, including to personalize, provide, and improve our services, to contact you to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, and to analyze how you use the Services. In certain cases, we may also share some Personal Information with third parties, but only as described below. 

As noted in the [Terms of Service](http://grooveapp.com/terms), we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us personal information, please contact us at support@grooveapp.com. 

### Will Groove ever change this Privacy Policy?

We’re constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well, but we will alert you to changes by placing a notice on the website at http://www.grooveapp.com/, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. Please note that if you’ve opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven’t provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used.

### What Information does Groove Collect?

#### Information You Provide to Us:

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us. For example, if you sign in to the Services through a third party site or service or otherwise connect your third party accounts to the Services, we may have access to some contents or information in those third-party accounts, such as your email address or log-in credentials, in order to provide Services to you. You understand that any such information transmitted to our Services is covered by this Privacy Policy. Certain information may be required to take advantage of some of our features. 

We may communicate with you if you’ve provided us the means to do so. For example, if you’ve given us your email address, we may send you promotional email offers, or email you about your use of the Services. Also, we may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. This confirmation helps us make our communications with you more interesting and improve our services. If you do not want to receive communications from us, please indicate your preference by emailing us at support@grooveapp.com. 

#### Information Collected Automatically

Whenever you interact with our Services, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or device, which may include your IP address, device identification, “cookie” information, the type of browser and/or device you’re using to access our Services, and the page or feature you requested. “Cookies” are identifiers we transfer to your browser or device that allow us to recognize your browser or device and tell us how and when pages and features in our Services are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or device to prevent or limit your device’s acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our features. 

If you click on a link to a third party website or service, a third party may also transmit cookies to you. Again, this Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties, and we aren’t responsible for their privacy policies and practices. Please be aware that cookies placed by third parties may continue to track your activities online even after you have left our Services, and those third parties may not honor “Do Not Track” requests you have set using your browser or device. 

We may use this data to improve the Services – for example, this data provides general statistics regarding use of the Services and can tell us how often users use a particular feature of the Services, and we can use that knowledge to make the Services interesting to as many users as possible. 

#### Information Collected From Other Websites and Do Not Track Policy

Through cookies we place on your browser or device, we may collect information about your online activity after you leave our Services. Just like any other usage information we collect, this information allows us to improve the Services and customize your online experience, and otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy. Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time. 

### Will Groove Share Any of the Personal Information it Receives?

**Information that’s been de-identified.** We may de-identify your Personal Information so that you are not identified as an individual, and provide that information to our service providers in order to improve our Services to you. For example, we may provide aggregate usage information to Google Analytics, who may use such information to analyze and review our Services internally. However, we never disclose aggregate usage or de-identified information to a partner (or allow a partner to collect such information) in a manner that would identify you as an individual person. 

**Agents:** We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you; for example, we may use a payment processing company to receive and process your credit card transactions for us. Also, we may employ resellers to assist with the implementation of and customer support for our Services. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. 

In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, Groove is potentially liable. 

**Business Transfers:** We may choose to buy or sell assets, and may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. We will provide an individual opt-out or opt-in choice before we share their data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. 

**Protection of Groove and Others:** We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our [Terms of Service](http://grooveapp.com/terms) and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Groove, our employees, our users, or others. 

Groove also may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

### Is Personal Information about me secure?

For your privacy and security, the third party account you chose to connect to our Services are protected by a password or any additional or different sign-on protections via that third party site or service. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing our Services. 

We endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other Personal Information we hold in our records, but unfortunately, we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. 

### What if I want to stop using the Groove products?

You may stop using our products by disconnecting your third party accounts from our Services. After you disconnect your third party accounts, we do not have access to or any control over the contents or information in your third party accounts, except we will only keep your email address on our record in order to provide our Services to you in the future (should you choose to resume the use of our Services). 

You may be able to view, update, and delete information in your third party account via that third party site or service. Again, we have no control over and are not responsible for the policies and practices of third party websites or services as to privacy or anything else. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at support@grooveapp.com. 

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: support@grooveapp.com. 

### What choices do I have?

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. 

You may be able to disconnect your third party accounts from our Services as explained above. When you do so, however, we may maintain a copy of your email address in our records. 

Groove acknowledges that individuals have the right to access the personal information/data that we maintain about them.  An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his query to support@grooveapp.com. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. 

### Privacy Shield Principles

Groove Labs Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Groove Labs Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>. 

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Groove Labs Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Groove Labs Inc. at: 

Legal Department   
Groove Labs, Inc.   
660 4th Street #684   
San Francisco, CA 94107   
email: support@grooveapp.com 

Groove Labs Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacyshield/for-eu-consumers> for more information and to file a complaint. 

As a last resort and under limited circumstances, individuals with unresolved complaints may invoke a binding arbitration option before a Privacy Shield Panel.

Groove is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
